<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Blog]]></title><description><![CDATA[Roy's Personal Blog.]]></description><link>https://roy-lee.github.io/</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2019 05:21:21 GMT</lastBuildDate><item><title><![CDATA[Bangkok Trip Day 3]]></title><description><![CDATA[Woke up and walked around the accomodation vicinity in search for breakfast. Yea, it might sound crazy I know, but this is my first time…]]></description><link>https://roy-lee.github.io//thailand-trip-day-3/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://roy-lee.github.io//thailand-trip-day-3/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Woke up and walked around the accomodation vicinity in search for breakfast. Yea, it might sound crazy I know, but this is my first time walking in the opposite direction of the train station in 3 days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Found a small store selling meatball noodles and grabbed one of the beef bowl for 50 Baht. The taste was pretty decent,albeit the portion was a bit small (just slightly bigger than the Boat Noodle I had near Victory Monument on Day 1). Grabbed a Cha Yen (Milk Tea) with pearl for 25 Baht and called a Grab to head to the Grand Palace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the taxi ride, the driver recommended me to go to Wat Pho instead for 3 reasons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The weather is extremely hot.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It is a hotspot for tourist, so I’ll probably need to queue for a long while.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The entrance fee is about 400-500 baht.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It closes at 3pm.
I was also told that if I really want to, I can visit the Grand Palace after touring Wat Pho Temple!
So I did and went to Wat Pho first instead. There were quite some tourists but the queue is almost non-existent because the entrance ticket is 200 baht and you can proceed right in without bag check.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The interior of the temple looks great! There were plenty of Monk/Buddha statues. The buildings and architectures are unique and beauty! Makes you wonder how did they do it and the significance behind them. Well, if you want to, you can probably pay a couple of hundred bahts for a tour guide, or simply enjoy and appreciate the beauty of those artifacts in the moment and Google it at your free time. (Yes I went in blindly not knowing what to expect.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Deep inside the temple lies the world largest reclining Buddha.
Extract from Wikipedia:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A reclining Buddha is a statue that represents Buddha lying down and is a major iconographic and statuary pattern of Buddhism.It represents the historical Buddha during his last illness, about to enter the parinirvana.
Inside here, you’ll need to take your shoes and put it in a plastic bag provided. Inside this hall you can see the enormous statue of the reclining Buddha stretching from head to toe. I did not have any dedicated camera with me to capture this beauty, so I just had to do with my trusty OnePlus 6.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Be prepared for spoilers if you have yet to travel there before!! This is my own experience, takeaway and lesson from the following activity. If you want to experience it on your own, skip the below!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One activity to do inside this hall was “Coin Dropping”. You simply have to pay 20 baht and the staff will pass you a bowl full of coins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You need to drop those coins into the many bowls which stretched across the length of the hall. How you provision your coins to each bowl was entirely up to you. Again, as I mentioned, I went in blindly, not knowing what to expect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So initially, I grabbed a couple of coins at the start and dropped them into the first bowl. I did that because I looked at my bowl of coins and compared it with all the bowls in the hall and thought to myself: “There’s plenty of coins enough for all of the bowls in this hall.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then this is where the fun begins. The satisfying sound of the coins dropping into the bowl, the action of dropping those coins, it was quite fun to me! It’s like a “touristy” thing one would do over there. But as I gradually reach the bowl in the middle of the stretch, I realised, my coins were not sufficient for the rest of the journey. I switched from my dropping “a couple of coins” to “2 coins per bowl”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was an improvement. I can last a few more bowls than what I could do with my previous method. But as I reach towards the end of my journey, I realised I did not have enough coins for the remaning bowls. So I switched from “2 coins per bowl” to just 1 coin each. It was a futile attempt. I did not successfully complete the entire coin journey. There were some bowls at the end which I did not put any coins into.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was enlightened by this simple activity. Imagine that those stretch of bowls is a journey of a job/project/work. And those coins which I had initially was my effort. Now, initially, everything is fun and exciting because it is a fresh project. There are so many things to explore and do. So I put in a lot of effort at the start. Towards the middle of the project, I realised that I overestimated my efforts and it’s becoming very draining. I can’t go on like this all the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So by putting lesser and lesser effort, I thought I could complete the journey. But this turns out to be wrong. The lesson was never about putting lesser and lesser effort. The lesson is to look ahead, plan ahead, provision your efforts with estimates, don’t overdo things at the start only to crumble towards the end. It should go off with a bang(putting your remaning coins into the last bowl) instead of reducing your efforts towards the end(1 coin per bowl).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This coin dropping acitivty was simple yet enlightening. At least for me. This was my own experience and I hope you had tried this activity and come up with your own conclusion before reading mine. If not, well, it’s a free lesson then!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After finishing this activity, I went around taking photos and exited the temple shortly. Remember to drink plenty of water as the weather is extremely hot. For those people who intend to travel alone as well, take note that if you faint, no one trustable will be beside you. You’ll be a very easy prey to someone who have malicious intent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The above was a very gentle reminder by the taxi driver who shot me the question while I was going there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After visiting Wat Pho, I wanted to visit the Grand Palace. So I followed the huge stretch of wall surrounding the palace and headed to the entrance. As I was approaching the entrace, a local tuktuk driver came up to me and asked where I was going. I told him I was heading to Grand Palace and he immediately told me it was close. I looked at my watch and realised it was 3pm already. The palace is closed. What a bummer. He offered me to visit 2 other locations but I have no intentions of go to those places.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I walked towards On Lok Yun from Wat Pho(as recommended by the previous taxi driver). It was about 10-15 minutes walk under the hot sun so I recommend wearing a hat and shades if you have it with you. Water is a must. Keep your eyes peeled for vehicles(especially those who are travelling alone). The culture and traffic flow there is not as structured as Singapore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Upon reaching On Lok Yun, I took a look at the menu and found out they serve brunch sets! Bacon, ham, eggs and saugages! I ordered one of those and it was really pretty good. I mean, there’s no WOW factor for me, but I can say at least say it’s pretty good, especially if you’re taking a break from long walks and the scorching hot sun. I was told this is a common place for tourist especially Singaporeans See? I went in blindly again. This trip was supposed to be a free and easy and carefree trip, and it sure is!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After eating the brunch set, I called a Grab and went to Pratunam. Lesson for me: double check your GPS location if you copy and pasted your location from Google! If traffic jam wasn’t bad enough, the GPS auto-corrected the location to another place(might be based on postal code). So the journey took about 20 minutes extra for me to reach Pratunam.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I reached there, first thing I did was to buy a shirt. My current shirt has been stained with sweat (eww) from the temple visit and the hot sun. I could have went back to my accomodation and get changed but I’d probably be too lazy to come out again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Went to change into the new shirt immediately after purchasing. Went to the 3 common shopping places around that area.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pratunam Market&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Platinum Shopping Mall&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Palladium IT Pratunam (Mall)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Took a looksie and walked around for a bit but did not buy anything because most stuffs are for girls and I did my shopping on Day 1 at Chatuchak. Most of the things there, like I said previously, are repetitive. Even the prices are too. But you can try to bargain and see if you can get your goods for lower. When I came out of the mall, it was already dark. So I walked towards Talad Neon Night Market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over here at Talad Neon Night Market, there are plenty of food stalls and small shops. I went to grab a plate of pork ribs and a rice to settle for dinner. It was pretty okay. Ordered a Cha Yen and sat down to rest. Walked the market for a bit and decided to go back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Intersting fact:
Grab Bike(Win) is actually GrabBike(Almost-win). Reason?
There is no auto direct translation + sending of photos in the Grab Bike chat with drivers. Grab Car/Taxi have the ability to receive translated Thai to English texts on the go and photos of your surroundings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I’m guessing you can say, “cant you just Google translate his texts in your browser/app?”
Yes I did. But all the driver kept replying was “send me a picture” I told him I could not because there was no such function. He then proceeded to say I lied to him and people will hurt me(in Google translate). Safe to say he already got my accomodation address and could be waiting for me downstairs(I even gave him a description of what I was wearing). I told him I’m sorry for wasting his time and I’ll cancel it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, to be fair, I honestly did nothing wrong and have everything to prove if he comes at me. But lucky me, when I took another Grab(taxi this time) back, there were no one in the dark alley(must be thanks to the temple visit earlier in the day, heh). The difference in price between GrabTaxi and GrabBike is about 50 baht.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Went back and took a nice shower and break before calling it a day! Will be doing laundry tomorrow to lessen the load back home!&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Bangkok Trip Day 2]]></title><description><![CDATA[Slept in in the morning till 10am. Felt very well rested. Did not rushed to go anywhere. Got washed up and set off to Siam in the noon to…]]></description><link>https://roy-lee.github.io//thailand-trip-day-2/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://roy-lee.github.io//thailand-trip-day-2/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Slept in in the morning till 10am. Felt very well rested. Did not rushed to go anywhere. Got washed up and set off to Siam in the noon to shop and eat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Upon reaching Siam Discovery, got called up by my client to do some work. Didn’t bring my laptop out with me and had to settle with using a phone. Got some of it rectified and told him I’d finish the rest when I get back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Went to MBK and looked around the stores they had in this large shopping mall. Bought a full screen tempered glass protector for 200 baht. Lady was kind enough to give me a discount when every other stores nearby were selling at 250-300 baht.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Went to have lunch at Katsuya. Double cheese fried chicken rice was on the menu and I was sold. It turned out ok. Wasn’t the best but definitely not the worst. Continued walking around the stores and bought myself a inflatable bunny ear hat for 199 baht! It was the one Rosa Salazar (actress of Alita) was wearing when she was in Korea! It looked really really cute!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Went upstairs and got myself a Thai Iced Milk Tea by Cha Tra Mue. An original local Thai tea shop. To be honest, it was a little too sweet for me (for someone who have sweet tooth). If you’re getting one for yourself, you can probably try another flavour!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Walked past an anime shop and damn, they really sell a lot of anime merchandise! It’s like a happy place for weebs (yes, I’m an ocasional nerd/weeb). Asked them for Gunnm/Alita merch but they told me they only have 2 mangas. A volumne of the main arc and a volume of Last Order. A bit dissapointed, frankly. Ended up buying OnePiece merch for my brother! Those merchs look pretty sick!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Went back to accomodations to put my things down and got to work. Watched Game Of Thrones too. A little whiskey with Game Of Thrones will never go wrong. It was the perfect evening. Having a paid assignment while you’re travelling essentially means you’re travelling for free (yes, you still pay for it. But at least it cushion some of your expenses). Admittedly, no one likes their holiday to be interrupted with work. But I came here to do what I like. Eat, drink, shop, see, work; these amount to pretty much what I have in mind! Besides, I brought my laptop overseas for a reason.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Should probably spend more time outside for Day 3!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;PSA&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re watching Game Of Thrones, please do not skip their opening. Please enjoy the music but more importantly, pay attention to the opening scene. It tells a story on its own (as it has always been).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Watch S08E01 and S08E02 opening scenes and find the difference. You’ll thank me later.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Bangkok Trip Day 1]]></title><description><![CDATA[Went to Chatuchak about 9am in the morning. Grabbed a quick fried rice for breakfast. They have interesting translation for their menu…]]></description><link>https://roy-lee.github.io//thailand-trip-day-1/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://roy-lee.github.io//thailand-trip-day-1/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Went to Chatuchak about 9am in the morning. Grabbed a quick fried rice for breakfast. They have interesting translation for their menu.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Walked wayyyy too many steps at Chatuchak. Bought many stuffs at a cheap price(yay) for family and myself. Notable stuffs include a pair of boots and a cardigan. Many stores did not carry OnePlus 6 accessories, which is sad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Had coconut ice cream as well. It is probably one of the “must-have” if you are at Chatuchak Weekend Market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was a promotion where promoters were giving out free ice cold sugarless Pepsi drinks in the sorching hot day. A very refreshing drink if you have been walking for too long.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Went to visit the Victory Monument. Did not physically went down to visit the monument, but took photos of it from the bridge across it. It was quite the sight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Had lunch at Rue Thong Boat Noodle place. It serves bite-sized bowls of noodles for cheap! You can try different flavours of their noodles as one is simply not enough. People over there stack bowls and bowls on their table. Some even going up to 10s and 20s of it! I had 3 and called it a day. It was great! But wasn’t feelng very hungry (weird because I’ve walked about 20000 steps in Chatuchak).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interesting events:
I was guided to seat with a local in the restaurant. After her food came, as she was eating it, she had a bit of runny nose. So I offered her some tissues. Now, while I was eating my noodles, I wanted to order a drink. However, she offered to buy me a drink instead! I thanked her and she left before I finished my meal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While returning back to hotel, as I was in the train, a female tourist fainted in the middle of the train ride. Her eyes literally rolled back and she collapsed like a dead weight. Her boyfriend tried to lift her up but she wasn’t responding. After about 15 seconds later, she got up and sat on a seat. A local offered her some oilment for her to apply.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PSA: Heat injury(heatstroke) is real. Please remember to drink up every so often! Especially when the weather over here is socrching hot and you’ve lost plenty of water throughout the day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, the locals over here are very nice! Taxi drivers as well! Even though there’s some language barrier, but we still get to communicate through basic English and hand signs!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Went back to hotel to put down all my loots for the day. Proceed to work on some freelance projects all the way from 6pm to 10pm. Mind you, I have not had dinner yet. Wanted to get something simple to eat nearby but there was no stores around the vicinity of my accomodation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I took a train to Sukhumvit, in hopes of finding a decent place with decent food. Went to Terminal 21 shopping mall, only to find out their stores in the mall are all closed. No surprise. Went down the lane and got myself in the alley of the Devil’s Playground. They have bars and clubs along this alley. But not a single restaurant which specialise in serving food. Grabbed a piece of Alfredo pizza outside one of the bar and ate it. Afterwards, I randomly picked a bar with a live band and got myself a Long Island. They have a food menu which was still serving late at this timing, which is different from Singapore’s last order timing at a bar. Got myself a sphagetti and settled with that for dinner. Had one last Jägermeister and called it a night. Took a taxi back to hotel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Might have went slightly over the budget for Day 1. But that’s taking into account that most of the shopping for the entire trip is done in Chatuchak weekend market. As per my previous 2 experiences in Bangkok, most of the things they sell are very repetitive, even in a couple of MRT Stations away. It’s mostly what you have seen in Chatuchak. Everything else is either international brand or extremely niche hipster goods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Probably will chillout a bit more for Day 2.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Bangkok Trip Day 0]]></title><description><![CDATA[Got to the airport early. Bought SIM card in the plane! (EXTREMELY CONVENIENT for 299Baht!!) Forgot that Singaporean passport still need to…]]></description><link>https://roy-lee.github.io//thailand-trip-day-0/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://roy-lee.github.io//thailand-trip-day-0/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Got to the airport early.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bought SIM card in the plane! (EXTREMELY CONVENIENT for 299Baht!!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Forgot that Singaporean passport still need to fill up immigration card. Passed the opportunity while on the plane (YIKES). Could have shaved off about 10-15mins.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Took a Grab to accomodation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Place is nice but soap ran out and there’s a couple of annoying mosquitoes (YIKES).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Preparation for Chatuchak weekend market later!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just a quick and dirty draft. More pictures will come again later!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For now, nights.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Hello World]]></title><description><![CDATA[1st attempt at trying out ReactJS + GatsbyJS + Github Pages for blogging! Gatsby Documentation Gatsby Starter Blog Gatsby with Github Pages…]]></description><link>https://roy-lee.github.io//hello-world/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://roy-lee.github.io//hello-world/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;1st attempt at trying out ReactJS + GatsbyJS + Github Pages for blogging!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gatsbyjs.org/docs/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Gatsby Documentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/gatsbyjs/gatsby-starter-blog&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Gatsby Starter Blog&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gatsbyjs.org/docs/how-gatsby-works-with-github-pages/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Gatsby with Github Pages&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gatsby purely uses markdown for blog posts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CSS are used too, of course. But that is a concern for another day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For now, a simple blogging platform would do.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>